Guide to the Harvey Reissig papers, 1969-2010.
Reissig, Harvey papers
- Series I. Research, Projects, and Assessments
  - Subseries Ic. Abroad
    - International Association for the Plant Protection Sciences (IAPPS), Dec 2004 - Jan 2005, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Correspondence
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Romania (1 of 5), 1982, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Copy of Romanian facts, brochure for Romanian Research Institute for Plant Protection
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Romania (2 of 5), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Includes color photos
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Romania (3 of 5), 1982, 1993-1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Booklet with translated title: The 40-year-old Fruit Tree Plant or Statiunea Pomicola Voinesti la 40 de Ani
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Romania (4 of 5), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Includes color photos; includes Romanian money
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Romania (5 of 5), 1982, 1992, 1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Includes data sheets and handwritten notes; business cards; brochure for Romanian Research Institute for Plant Protection
    - Apple Project in Hungary - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) (1 of 2), 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Includes business cards; published research papers; The Story of Sarospatak Academy by M. Eugene Osterhaven; booklet on plant protection; map of Hungary; booklet on fruit juice; travel brochure; includes color photos and photo negatives
    - Apple Project in Hungary - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) (2 of 2), 1994-1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Correspondence; published reports; includes a sticker for an institute; brochure for the Ministry of Agriculture in Hungary; brochure for travel in Budapest; blank postcard; brochure for Tuzser, Hungary
    - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Project in Armenia, 1998-2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Includes booklet on Armenian Scientific-Research Institute of Plant Protection; includes business cards; correspondence; booklet on the wines of Amenia; includes passenger tickets and baggage checks
    - Course Outline for Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Training Workshop - Bangladesh, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Includes brochures for The New York State Integrated Pest Management Program; projector lesson sheets
    - International Organisation for Biological and Integrated Control (IOBC) Conference - Italy, 2002-2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Includes housing catelog; business cards; booklet on Agricultural Institute of San Michele All'Adige; copy of a map; correspondence; plane ticket
    - International Organisation for Biological and Integrated Control (IOBC) Conference - Spain, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Includes business cards
    - Integrated Fruit Protection (IFP) Conference - Avignon, 2007-2009, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Registration forms; ticketing information; copy of tourist guide of Provence
    - International Dwarf Fruit Tree Association (IDFTA) Conference - New Zealand, 1999-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Correspondece; itineraries; copy of tourist guide of Auckland
    - International Fruit Tree Association Tour - Nova Scotia, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Registration and itinerary papers
    - Chile - Research Trip, 1988-1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Map of Chile; receipts; business cards
    - Brazil - Research Trip for Apple Production (1 of 2), 1991-1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Includes trip information; business cards; correspondence and faxes; research reports
    - Brazil - Research Trip for Apple Production (2 of 2), 1993-1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Includes business cards; handwritten notes for what to say to Brazilian Growers; copy of Dormex - Technical Data Sheet; report on Uptake and metabolism of Hydrogen Cyanaminde in plants - Federal Republic of Germany
    - China Project - Collaboration in Sustainable Agriculture and Development, 1998-1999, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Includes a published article in the Fruit Grower of China's apple production
    - Asian Integrated Pest Management (IPM), 1981-1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes research papers on IPM in South East Asia
    - Management of Pest insects of Rice in Farmers' Fields in the Philippines, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      With E. A. Heinrichs, L. Antonio, M. M. Salac, A. C. Santiago, and A. M. Tenorio; printed in the Netherlands
    - Insecticide-Induced Resurgence of the Brown Planthopper on Rice Varieties with Different Levels of Resistance, 1982-02 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      With E. A. Heinrichs and S. L. Valencia and the International Rice Research Institute in Manila, Philippines
    - Effects of Insecticides on N. lugens and its Predators, 1982-02 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Management of Arthropods on Columnar Apple Trees Using Exlusionary Cages, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      With D. S. Lawson, J. P. Nyrop, and S. K. Brown
  - Subseries Id. Industry Testing
    - Bayer Crop Science - Insecticide Protocol - Calypso, 2001-2007, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Correspondence; handwritten notes; cautionary statements; Pflanzenschutz Nachrichten Bayer Journal Vol. 60
    - Arvesta Protocol, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Includes presentation on Kanemite
    - DuPont Protocol, 2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Includes technical bulletin for Avaunt WG (insect control agent)
    - DuPont Crop Protection, 2004-2008, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes Reissig's business card
    - Cerexagri Laboratory Tests, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Dow AgroSciences Testing, 2000-2008, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Includes technical bulletins for Dow, Valent, and Rohm and Haas Company
    - Gowan Company Development Protocol, 2003, 2007, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Syngenta Crop Protection, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Petro-Canada - Spray Oil Technical Bulletins, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Companies - Insect Trapping, 1956, 1974, 1980-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Netting samples; dealer catalog; product catalogs; catalogs for supplier of essential oils, balsams, concentrated flavors, perfume oils, and certified colors
- Series I. Grant Files
  - Grants Reviewed (1 of 3), 1983-12-1986-01 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Grants Reviewed (2 of 3), 1985-01-1989-08 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Grants Reviewed (3 of 3), Aug 1990 - Jan 2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Apple Maggot - USDA Grant Application, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Apple Maggot Grant - Specific Cooperative Agreement (SCA), 1990-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Includes published article in Agricultural Research; final reports; progress reports; data sheets
  - Grant Proposals, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Grant Proposals, 1996-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Grant Proposals, 1997-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Grant Proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Armenian Grant, 1995-2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Article from New York's Food and Life Sciences Bulletin
  - Grant Proposals, 2003-11 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Pest Management Alternatives Program (PMAP) Grant, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Crops at Risk (CAR) Grant, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Northeastern Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Center Grant, 2004-01-2004-04 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Grant Proposals, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Pest Management Alternatives Program (PMAP) Grant, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Relevance Statement, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - A.J. Landers Grant Proposal, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Start of project was set in 2005
  - Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) Grant, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Correspondence for RAMP award
  - Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) Grant, 1966, 2003, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes flyers for Hershey festivals; U.S. Standards for Grades of Nectarines
  - Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) Grant, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) Grant, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pest Management Program for NY and New England Growers, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Grants.gov Guide, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Starker E. Wright - Apple Maggot Research Grant, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Apple Maggot Quarantine - California, 1990-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Apple Research and Development Grant, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Correspondence and progress report
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    With USDA, Kansas State University, New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), Lamont Fruit Farm, Inc., International Atomic Energy Agency, Entomological Society of America, University of Missouri, others
  - Correspondence, 1978, 1989-1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    With USDA, Consortium for International Crop Protection, New York State Home Wine Competition, New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), Entomological Society of America, The Canadian Entomologist, New South Wales Government, Thailand, others
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    With New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), New South Wales Government, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Centres de Recherche de Geneve, International Rice Research Institute, Colorado State University, Lincoln University, others
  - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    With New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), Michigan State University, International Rich Research Institute, Agriculture Canada, Entomological Society of America, American Wine Society,
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    With New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), Colorado State University, Council for International Exchange of Scholars, Ministry of Agriculture in Hungary, University of Kentucky, others
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    With Rohm and Haas Company, Iowa State University, Morris Arboretum of the University of Pennsylvania, Poland, Hungary, others
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    With Rohm and Haas Company, Japan, Michigan State University, USDA, New York State Home Wine Committee, Oregon State University, Brazil, others
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    With Rochester Institute of Technology, USDA, Food for the Hungry, Ontario, Michigan State University, others
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    With Colorado State University, University of Florida, others
- Series IV. Meetings, Committees, and Conferences
  - Syngenta Meeting - Las Vegas, 2007-2013 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - USDA Cooperative Agreement, 2005-05-2005-06 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Multistate Western Coordinating Committee, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES) Safety Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Statewide Fruit Industry Competitiveness and Profitability Committee, 1997-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Portland Meeting, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Map of Portland; driving directions; hotel room key holder; visitor guides
  - Orchard Pest and Disease Management Conference (OPDMC) - Portland, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Handwritten notes
  - New England, New York, Canadian Fruit Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Workshop, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) Operating Committee, 1984, 1990-1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Empty plastic packet of Hudson Valley Apple Crisps; brochures for CORE Values Northeast Apples; IPM promotions
  - Great Lakes Fruit Workers Conference, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Field Research Unit Study Committee Report, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Handwritten notes; map of proposed retention pond
  - Entomological Society of America (ESA) Eastern Branch - President, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Correspondence with Rod Youngman
  - Great Lakes Fruit Workers Conference - Ontario, Canada, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Azinphos-Methyl Usage Meeting, 2006-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Presentation slides, plane ticket and receipt
  - American Wine Society (AWS) Meeting, 2009-09 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Consortium for International Crop Protection (CICP) - Board of Directors, 2001-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Brochures; meeting minutes
  - Cumberland-Shenandoah Fruit Workers Conference (CSFWC) - Registration, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Series V. Miscellaneous
  - Bridge Club, 2001-2005 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Beginners bidding guide
  - David Combs - Performance Reviews, 2000-2012 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Includes staff performance dialogue form for Cynthia M. Smith
  - Cornell International Integrated Pest Management (IPM), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Includes China initiative, action plan for CICP, trip to Zimbabwe
  - Cornell Life Insurance, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Performance Review, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Department Memos, 1989-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Includes flyer for department programs
  - Dean's Report, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES) - Geneva Faculty, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Fello, Kate - Temporary Service Employee in Reissig Program, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Empire State Fruit and Vegetable Expo, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Old Talks - Projector Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Series VI. Slides
  Possibly relating to research trips
  - Slides, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    Includes Brazil
  - Slides, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Slovakia and Romania, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Slides, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Includes Thailand
  - Old Apple Maggot Slides, 1956-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Beneficial Insects, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Slides, 1979-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Includes the Philippines, International Rice Reseach Institute, Thailand
  - Slides, 1989-1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Slides, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Includes Thailand and mite resistance
  - Apple Maggot, 1977-1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Slides, 1982-1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Slides, 1981-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Slides, 1988-1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Slides, 1995-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Slides, 1998-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Integrated Pest Management (IPM), Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Slides transferred from box; out of order
  - Fruit Pests, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Wooly Apple Aphid, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - San Jose Scale, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - European Apple Sawfly, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Predatory Mate, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Spotted Tentiform Leafminer, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Series VII. Media
  - Photo Album - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) in Romania, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Photo Album - Integrated Pest Management (IPM) in Hungary, Undated (Box 7)
  - Compact FlashDrive, Undated; ZD-89 (Box 7)
  - New England Apple Pest Management Guide, 2000-2001; CD-3985 (Box 7)
  - Reduced-Risk Pest Management Programs for Eastern Tree Fruits USDA Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) - Summary of Year 3 Results, 2004; CD-3986 (Box 7)
  - Reduced-Risk Pest Management Programs for Eastern Tree Fruits USDA Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) - Summary of Year 4 Results, 2005; CD-3987 (Box 7)
  - Reduced-Risk Pest Management Programs for Eastern Tree Fruits USDA Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) - Summary of Year 1 Results, 2002; CD-3988 (Box 7)
  - Reduced-Risk Pest Management Programs for Eastern Tree Fruits USDA Risk Avoidance and Mitigation Program (RAMP) - Summary of Year 2 Results, 2003; CD-3989 (Box 7)
  - Reissig - Clutch, 2004; CD-3990 (Box 7)
  - Great Lakes Fruit Workers Conference, 2004; CD-3991 (Box 7)
  - Oriental Fruit Moth (OFM), 2004; CD-3992 (Box 7)
  - Reissig Expo, 2004; CD-3993 (Box 7)
  - Lake George - Oblique Banded Leafroller (OBLR) - PowerPoint, 2004; CD-3994 (Box 7)
  - Reissig - Oriental Fruit Moth (OFM) - WOPDMC, 2005; CD-3995 (Box 7)
  - Lake George, 2005; CD-3996 (Box 7)
  - Apple Maggot - PowerPoint, 2005; CD-3997 (Box 7)
  - Quebec, 2005; CD-3998 (Box 7)
  - International Organisation for Biological and Integrated Control (IOBC) - PowerPoint, 2006; CD-3999 (Box 7)
  - International Organisation for Biological and Integrated Control (IOBC) - PowerPoint, 2006; CD-4000 (Box 7)
  - New England Oblique Banded Leafroller - PowerPoint, 2006; CD-4001 (Box 7)
  - FL Wines - 07, 2004-11-16; CD-4002 (Box 7)
  - Orchard Pest and Disease Management Conference (OPDMC), 2007; CD-4003 (Box 7)
  - Fruit and Vegetable Expo, 2007; CD-4004 (Box 7)
  - EB - Entomological Society of America - Apple Maggot - Organic, 2007; CD-4005 (Box 7)
  - Apple IPW Web Tests, 2009; CD-4006 (Box 7)
  - Second Generation Oblique Banded Leafroller - Fruit Damage, 2011; CD-4007 (Box 7)
  - New York Wine Industry Workshop and Finger Lakes Grape Growing Convention, 2012-03-01-2012-03-03; CD-4008 (Box 7)
  - Cumberland-Shenandoah Fruit Workers Conference (CSFWC) - Oriental Fruit Moth (OFM) Meeting - PowerPoint, Undated; CD-4009 (Box 7)
  - Agnello/Reissig Talks, Undated; CD-4010 (Box 7)
  - Assail VA Trust Fruit Consultant Presentation, Undated; CD-4011 (Box 7)
  - Photos from Joe, Undated; CD-4012 (Box 7)
  - Insect Photos from Joe O., Undated; CD-4013 (Box 7)
  - Photo Files from Joe O., Undated; CD-4014 (Box 7)
  - New York State Agricultural Experiment Station - Report of 2004 Proposals Received and Awards Made, 2004-09; CD-4015 (Box 7)
  - New York State Agricultural Experiment Station - Report of 2006 Proposals Received and Awards Made, 2006-09; CD-4016 (Box 7)